<bill session="113" type="s" number="2828" updated="2014-10-25T07:42:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation, to provide additional assistance to Ukraine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="573">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 573.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Estonia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latvia"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Moldova"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014 - Directs the President to impose three or more sanctions under this Act against:

 Rosoboronexport; any person that knowingly makes a significant investment in a special Russian crude oil project; or any entity owned by the government of the Russian Federation or controlled by its nationals that transfers or brokers the transfer to, or manufactures or sells defense articles transferred to, Syria or into the territory of a specified country without its government's consent. Defines "specified country" as Ukraine, Georgia, Moldova, or any other country of significant concern for purposes of this Act, such as Poland, Lithuania, Latvia, Estonia, and the Central Asia republics.

Authorizes the President, through the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce or the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury, to impose additional licensing requirements or other restrictions on the export of items for Russia's energy sector.

Directs the President to impose sanctions under this Act on Gazprom if it is withholding significant natural gas supplies from North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) member countries, or further withholds significant natural gas supplies from countries such as Ukraine, Georgia, or Moldova.

Sets forth sanctions against a foreign person, including executive officers of an entity, relating to:

 Export-Import Bank of the United States assistance, executive agency procurement, arms and dual-use item exports, U.S. property transactions, banking transactions, investing in or purchasing equity or debt instruments, and U.S. entry prohibition or visa revocation. Authorizes the President to waive the application of sanctions, or waive sanctions for a specific transaction, for purposes of U.S. national security, and with congressional notification.

Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to designate Ukraine, Georgia, and Moldova as major non-NATO allies for purposes of that Act and the Arms Export Control Act.

Provides assistance to Ukraine for: (1) the military, defense, energy, and civilian sectors; and (2) internally displaced persons.

Directs the Secretary of State to work with Ukrainian officials to help Ukraine reduce its dependence on natural gas imported from the Russian Federation.

Directs the Chairman of the Broadcasting Board of Governors to submit to Congress a plan for increasing the quantity of Russian-language broadcasting into the countries of the former Soviet Union in order to counter Russian Federation propaganda. Requires such plan to prioritize broadcasting into Ukraine, Georgia, and Moldova by the Voice of America (VOA) and Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty.</summary>
</bill>
