<bill session="113" type="h" number="4435" updated="2014-11-08T06:59:47-05:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22T12:17:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-22T12:17:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Howard P. "Buck" McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Howard P. "Buck" McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Federal Information Technology Acquisition Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">World War I Memorial Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2015 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2014-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Tactical Air and Land Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Seapower and Projection Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-01">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-01">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 61 - 0.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-13T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 113-446.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-13T13:33:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="329">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 329.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-19T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>FILING AUTHORITY - Mrs. Walorski asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to file a supplemental report on H.R. 4435.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-19T17:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Armed Services, H. Rept. 113-446, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-19T19:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 585 Reported to House. All points of order against the bills are waived. General debate shall not exceed one hour. After general debate the bills shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee of Armed Services for H.R. 4435, an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113-44 shall be considered as adopted and considered as an original bill for the purposes of amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 585 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 585.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4541-4680" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4549-4671" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against the bills are waived. General debate shall not exceed one hour. After general debate the bills shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee of Armed Services for H.R. 4435, an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113-44 shall be considered as adopted and considered as an original bill for the purposes of amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 585 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Chris Stewart to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4435.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T20:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 585, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T20:42:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Blumenauer amendment until a time to be annnounced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 585, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gohmert amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T20:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 585, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Loretta Sanchez amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:00:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Loretta Sanchez amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Loretta Sanchez demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 585, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lamborn amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 585, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment No. 5, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:19:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garamendi amendment No. 5, as modified, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garamendi demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 585, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Daines amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Daines amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cooper demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 585, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lamborn amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lamborn moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20T21:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4435 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T01:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 590 Reported to House. Rule provides further consideration of H.R. 4435. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in part A of the report. At the conclusion of consideration for amendment, the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such further amendments as may have been adopted. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions. The rule also provides for consideration of H.R. 3361. All points of order against consideration are waived. The bill, as amended by part B of the report</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4712-4714" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>WITHDRAWN DEMAND FOR RECORDED VOTE - Mr. Garamendi asked unanimous consent to withdraw his demand for a recorded vote on amendment No. 5, as modified, and printed in House Report 113-455 to the end that the amendment stand rejected pursuant to the earlier voice vote on the amendment from May 20, 2014. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DISPOSITION OF AMENDMENT NO. 5 - The Chair announced that, without objection, the request for a recorded vote having been withdrawn, the Garamendi amendment No. 5, as modified, stands rejected in accordance with the previous voice vote thereon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4435 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4716-4782" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McKinley Part A amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McKinley amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Waxman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T18:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon En Bloc amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T18:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Westmoreland Part A amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T18:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shimkus Part A amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:00:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Shimkus amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Welch demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) Part A amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:17:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 10, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) Part A amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 11, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Heck (WA) amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jenkins amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jenkins amendment No. 15, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Loebsack demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lamborn amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T20:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lamborn amendment No. 17, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T20:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schiff amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T20:14:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schiff amendment No. 21, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Schiff demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T20:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 24, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T20:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon En Bloc amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T20:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hastings (WA) amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T20:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon En Bloc amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T21:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon En Bloc amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T21:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon En Bloc amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon En Bloc amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T21:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 590, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon En Bloc amendment No. 7, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T21:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T21:41:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T21:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4435 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4804-4812" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4435.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4809" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4809" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Peters (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4809-4811" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4810" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Peters (CA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add a new section to the bill titled Provisions Relating to Wages, Discrimination, Outsourcing Jobs, Student Loans, and Baggage Fees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4811" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 194 - 227 (Roll no. 239).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4811" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="240" datetime="2014-05-22T12:17:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 325 - 98 (Roll no. 240).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 4435.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="425">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 425.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS25" subcommittee="Tactical Air and Land Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS26" subcommittee="Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS29" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS28" subcommittee="Seapower and Projection Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="145"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="585"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="590"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="590"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="124"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="330"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1359"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1494"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1756"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1824"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1898"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2185"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2310"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2882"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3687"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3805"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3840"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3960"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4094"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4342"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4359"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4371"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4489"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4628"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4630"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4705"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4729"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4730"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="59"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1684"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1906"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2217"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2264"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2289"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2294"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2334"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2357"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2481"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2486"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Djibouti"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h664"/>
    <amendment number="h665"/>
    <amendment number="h666"/>
    <amendment number="h667"/>
    <amendment number="h668"/>
    <amendment number="h669"/>
    <amendment number="h670"/>
    <amendment number="h671"/>
    <amendment number="h672"/>
    <amendment number="h673"/>
    <amendment number="h674"/>
    <amendment number="h675"/>
    <amendment number="h676"/>
    <amendment number="h677"/>
    <amendment number="h678"/>
    <amendment number="h679"/>
    <amendment number="h680"/>
    <amendment number="h681"/>
    <amendment number="h682"/>
    <amendment number="h683"/>
    <amendment number="h684"/>
    <amendment number="h685"/>
    <amendment number="h686"/>
    <amendment number="h687"/>
    <amendment number="h688"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/9/2014--Introduced.
National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 - Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2015.

Authorizes appropriations to DOD for: (1) procurement, including aircraft, missiles, weapons and tracked combat vehicles, ammunition, shipbuilding and conversion, and other procurement; (2) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund; (3) research, development, test, and evaluation; (4) operation and maintenance; (5) active and reserve military personnel; (6) Working Capital Funds; (7) the Joint Urgent Operational Needs Fund; (8) chemical agents and munitions destruction; (9) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities; (10) the Defense Inspector General; (11) the Defense Health Program; (12) the Armed Forces Retirement Home; (13) chemical demilitarization; (14) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program; (15) Guard and reserve forces facilities; and (16) base closure and realignment activities. Sets forth provisions or requirements concerning: (1) military personnel policy, including education and training; (2) military pay and allowances; (3) military health care; (4) acquisition policy and management; (5) DOD organization and management; (6) financial matters; (7) civilian personnel matters; (8) matters relating to foreign nations; (9) overseas contingency operations; (10) military construction; (11) real property and facilities administration; and (12) military land withdrawals.

Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2015 for military construction for the Armed Forces and defense agencies.</summary>
</bill>
