<bill session="113" type="h" number="3326" updated="2014-11-08T06:50:25-05:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trinity County Land Exchange Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for an exchange of land between the United States and the Trinity Public Utilities District of Trinity County, California, involving a parcel of National Forest System land in Shasta-Trinity National Forest.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412511"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2013-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2013--Introduced.
Trinity County Land Exchange Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), if the Trinity Public Utilities District of Trinity County, California, conveys to the Secretary of the Interior all right, title, and interest of the District in the Sky Ranch parcel (Parcel A), to convey to the District all right, title, and interest of the United States in certain land in the Shasta-Trinity National Forest near the Weaverville Airport in Trinity County (Parcel B).

Intends for such land exchange to be an equal value exchange.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Redding Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to administer Parcel A as public land.</summary>
</bill>
