<bill session="113" type="s" number="2141" updated="2014-10-25T07:36:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sunscreen Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide an alternative process for review of safety and effectiveness of nonprescription sunscreen active ingredients and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2014-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2014-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Harkin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="568">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 568.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-09-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5715-5720" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5715-5720" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4250"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4250"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Sunscreen Innovation Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish a process for the review and approval of over-the-counter (OTC) sunscreens.

Require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to review and determine whether OTC sunscreens are generally recognized as safe and effective and ensure that any sunscreens marketed in the United States are appropriately labeled.

Makes sunscreens that have been marketed for five continuous years in the United States or other countries and in sufficient quantity eligible for review under this Act.

Establishes a framework for the review and approval by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) of OTC sunscreens with new active ingredients. Sets forth time frame requirements for review. Requires applications for review to include safety and efficacy data as well as adverse drug experience information.

Directs the Secretary to report on the progress made in issuing timely decisions on the safety and effectiveness of OTC sunscreens.

Requires the Secretary to make determinations on the testing and labeling of aerosol sunscreens and on whether a sunscreen may contain a label indicating a sun protection factor (SPF) greater than 50.</summary>
</bill>
