<bill session="113" type="s" number="1893" updated="2014-10-25T07:34:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Transportation Security Administration to implement best practices and improve transparency with regard to technology acquisition programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412493"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2719"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2013--Introduced.
Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to develop, update biennially, and report to Congress a strategic multiyear technology investment plan, which may include a classified addendum to report sensitive transportation security risks, technology vulnerabilities, or other sensitive security information.

Directs the Administrator to analyze the TSA's acquisition of any security-related technology to determine if it is justified. Requires the Administrator, 30 days before any TSA award of a contract for acquisitions exceeding $30 million, to report to Congress the results of the analysis and certify that the security benefits justify the contract cost.

Directs the appropriate TSA acquisition official to establish certain performance baseline requirements before any TSA security-related technology acquisition. Requires that official to review and assess each acquisition for meeting the baseline requirements and to report those results to Congress.

Requires the Administrator, before the procurement of additional quantities of equipment to fulfill a TSA mission need, to utilize, to the extent practicable, any existing units in the TSA's inventory to meet that need.

Directs the Administrator to report annually to Congress on TSA's goals for contracting with small and disadvantaged businesses.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to assess TSA's implementation of GAO recommendations regarding the acquisition of security-related technology that were made before enactment of this Act.

Directs the GAO to evaluate TSA's progress in implementing this Act.</summary>
</bill>
