<bill session="113" type="s" number="2520" updated="2014-10-25T07:39:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FOIA Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the Freedom of Information Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3942"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3942-3944" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1211"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2014--Introduced.
FOIA Improvement Act of 2014 - Amends the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to: (1) require federal agencies to make agency records that can be disclosed under such Act available for public inspection in an electronic format, (2) limit the authority of an agency to charge a fee if the agency misses a deadline for complying with a FOIA request, (3) establish a presumption in favor of disclosure and prohibit the application of exemptions from FOIA based on technicalities, (4) expand the authority and duties of the Chief FOIA Officer of each agency for promoting compliance with the FOIA disclosure requirements, and (5) establish a Chief FOIA Officers Council to develop recommendations for increasing compliance with FOIA requirements.

Requires the head of each federal agency to: (1) review agency regulations and issue regulations for the disclosure of records in accordance with the amendments to FOIA made by this Act, and (2) include in such regulations procedures for engaging in dispute resolution through the FOIA Public Liaison and the Office of Government Information Services.

Expands the program for the efficient management of federal agency records to require agency heads to establish procedures for: (1) identifying records of general interest or use to the public that are appropriate for public disclosure, and (2) posting such records in a publicly-accessible electronic format.

Prohibits the authorization of additional funds to carry out the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
