<bill session="113" type="s" number="1683" updated="2014-12-08T18:48:57-05:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-04">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the transfer of naval vessels to certain foreign recipients, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2013-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="247">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 247.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6355" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-04" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T12:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="12"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3973"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/14/2013--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Title I: Transfer of Excess United States Naval Vessels - Naval Vessels Transfer Act of 2013 - (Sec. 102) Authorizes the President to transfer on a grant basis to: (1) Mexico, the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates CURTS and MCCLUSKY; and (2) Thailand, the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates RENTZ and VANDEGRIFT.

Authorizes the President to transfer on a sale basis the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates TAYLOR, GARY, CARR, and ELROD to the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office of the United States (which is the Taiwan instrumentality designated pursuant to the Taiwan Relations Act).

Authorizes the President to transfer on a grant basis to Pakistan in each of FY2014-FY2016 one of the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates USS KLAKRING, USS DE WERT, and USS ROBERT G. BRADLEY 15 days after certifying to Congress that Pakistan is: (1) cooperating with the United States in counterterrorism and nonproliferation efforts, (2) not supporting terrorist activities against the United States in Afghanistan or elsewhere, (3) taking steps towards releasing Dr. Shakil Afridi, (4) taking steps to dismantle improvised explosive device (IED) networks, (5) providing humanitarian groups with access to detainees and other Pakistani civilians, and (6) ensuring that Pakistan's military and intelligence agencies are not intervening into Pakistan's political and judicial processes.

Authorizes the President to waive such certification requirements for U.S. national security interests.

Authorizes the President to transfer any vessel named in this Act to any country named in this Act such that the total number of vessels transferred to such country does not exceed the total number of vessels authorized for transfer to such country by this Act.

States that: (1) the value of such vessels transferred on a grant basis shall not be counted against the aggregate value of excess defense articles transferred to countries in any fiscal year under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961; (2) transfer costs shall be charged to the recipient; and (3) to the maximum extent practicable, the country to which a vessel is transferred shall have necessary vessel repair and refurbishment carried out at U.S. shipyards (including U.S. Navy shipyards).

Terminates transfer authority three years after enactment of this Act.

Title II: Additional Provisions - (Sec. 201) Amends the Arms Export Control Act to direct the President to notify Congress at least 30 days prior to a shipment of certain defense articles.

(Sec. 202) Directs the President to provide Congress with copies of any: (1) new presidential directives or policy guidance on national security, including on U.S. counterterrorism policies; and (2) directives or policy guidance that were issued on or after January 1, 2013, and prior to the date of the enactment of this Act.

(Sec. 203) Directs the President to provide Congress with initial and subsequent reports regarding: (1) each security assurance made by U.S. government officials to officials of each country in the Middle East, including such assurances made to Israel regarding its security and maintenance of its qualitative military edge; and (2) an analysis of the extent to which, and by what means, each such assurance has been and is continuing to be fulfilled.

(Sec. 205) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act to increase annual funds limits for transfers of excess defense articles.

(Sec. 206) Authorizes the President, for FY2014-FY2016, to enter into cooperative arrangements providing for the participation of foreign and U.S. military and civilian defense personnel for integrated air and missile defense programs in Southwest Asia.</summary>
</bill>
